Inspired by a True Friendship.
Green Book is a drama, comedy, history film directed by Peter Farrelly.
Tony Lip, a bouncer in 1962, is hired to drive pianist Don Shirley on a tour through the Deep South in the days when African Americans, forced to find
alternate accommodations and services due to segregation laws below the Mason-Dixon Line, relied on a guide called The Negro Motorist Green Book.
Tony Lip, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Dr. Don Shirley, played by Mahershala Ali.
Dolores, played by Linda Cardellini.
Johnny Venere, played by Sebastian Maniscalco.
Oleg, played by Dimiter D. Marinov.
George, played by Mike Hatton.
Green Book is a 2018 American biographical
comedy-drama film directed by Peter Farrelly.
Starring Viggo Mortensen and Mahershala Ali, the film is inspired by the true story of a 1962 tour of the Deep South by African-American pianist
Don Shirley and Italian-American bouncer and later actor Frank "Tony Lip" Vallelonga, who served as Shirley's driver and bodyguard.
Written by Farrelly alongside Lip's son Nick Vallelonga and Brian Hayes Currie, the film is
based on interviews with Lip and Shirley, as well as letters Lip wrote to his wife.
It is named after The Negro Motorist Green Book, a guide book for African-American
travelers founded by Victor Hugo Green in 1936 and published until 1966.
Green Book had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival
on September 11, 2018, where it won the People's Choice Award.
It was then theatrically released in the United States on November 16, 2018,
by Universal Pictures, and grossed $321 million worldwide.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for the performances of Mortensen and
Ali, although it also drew some criticism for its depiction of both race and Shirley.
Green Book received many awards and nominations.
It won the Academy Award for Best Picture, Best Original
Screenplay, and Best Supporting Actor (for Ali).
It also won the Producers Guild of America Award for Best Theatrical Motion Picture, the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy, and the
National Board of Review award for the best film of 2018, and was chosen as one of the top 10 films of the year by the American Film Institute.
Ali also won the Golden Globe, Screen Actors Guild, and
BAFTA Awards for Best Supporting Actor.
The film explores themes of friendship, southern usa,
based on true story, road trip, racism.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.